{"test_questions": [[{"question": "harvest", "opta": "autumn", "optb": "stockpile", "optc": "tractor", "optd": "crop", "ans": "D", "explanation": "To harvest something, one must have a crop, which is the essential element for this item. Autumn (choice a) is not the only time crops are harvested. There may not be enough of a crop to stockpile (choice b), and you can harvest crops without a tractor (choice c)."}, {"question": "desert", "opta": "cactus", "optb": "arid", "optc": "oasis", "optd": "flat", "ans": "B", "explanation": "A desert is an arid tract of land. Not all deserts are flat (choice d). Not all deserts have cacti or oases (choices a and c)."}, {"question": "book", "opta": "fiction", "optb": "pages", "optc": "pictures", "optd": "learning", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The necessary part of a book is its pages; there is no book without pages. Not all books are fiction (choice a), and not all books have pictures (choice c). Learning (choice d) may or may not take place with a book"}, {"question": "language", "opta": "tongue", "optb": "slang", "optc": "writing", "optd": "words", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Words are a necessary part of language. Slang is not necessary to language (choice b). Not all languages are written (choice c). Not all languages are spoken (choice a)."}, {"question": "school", "opta": "student", "optb": "report card", "optc": "test", "optd": "learning", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Without students, a school cannot exist; therefore, students are the essential part of schools. The other choices may be related, but they are not essential."}, {"question": "pain", "opta": "cut", "optb": "burn", "optc": "nuisance", "optd": "hurt", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Pain is suffering or hurt, so choice d is the essential element. Without hurt, there is no pain. A cut (choice a) or a burn (choice b) may cause pain, but so do many other types of injury. A nuisance (choice c) is an annoyance that may or may not cause pain."}, {"question": "gala", "opta": "celebration", "optb": "tuxedo", "optc": "appetizer", "optd": "orator", "ans": "A", "explanation": "A gala indicates a celebration, the necessary element  here. A tuxedo (choice  b) is not required garb at a gala, nor is an appetizer (choice c). A gala may be held without the benefit of anyone speaking (choice d)."}, {"question": "monopoly", "opta": "corrupt", "optb": "exclusive", "optc": "rich", "optd": "gigantic", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The essential part of a monopoly is that it involves exclusive ownership or control."}, {"question": "guitar", "opta": "band", "optb": "teacher", "optc": "songs", "optd": "strings", "ans": "D", "explanation": "A guitar does not exist without strings, so strings are an essential part of a guitar. A band is not necessary to a guitar (choice a). Guitar playing can be learned without a teacher (choice b). Songs are byproducts of a guitar (choice c)."}, {"question": "election", "opta": "president", "optb": "voter", "optc": "November", "optd": "nation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "An election does not exist without voters. The election of a president (choice a) is a byproduct. Not all elections are held in November (choice c), nor are they nationwide (choice d)."}, {"question": "shoe", "opta": "sole", "optb": "leather", "optc": "laces", "optd": "walking", "ans": "A", "explanation": "All shoes have a sole of some sort.Not all shoes are  made of leather (choice b); nor do they all have laces (choice c).Walking (choice d) is not essential to a shoe."}, {"question": "swimming", "opta": "pool", "optb": "bathing suit", "optc": "water", "optd": "life jacket", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Water is essential for swimming-without water, there is no swimming. The other choices are things that may or may not be present."}, {"question": "lightning", "opta": "electricity", "optb": "thunder", "optc": "brightness", "optd": "rain", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Lightning is produced from a discharge of electricity, so electricity is essential. Thunder and rain are not essential to the production of lightning (choices b and d). Brightness may be a byproduct of lightning, but it is not essential (choice c)."}]]}